

EDUCATION

SUMMARY

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai B.Tech SCSE 2019 CGPA = 9.04 Detail Oriented Computer Science Engineer with 8 months of experience as a Data Scientist at Launchpad.ai and 2+ years of experience as a Software Developer at Bank of America. Highly organized, self-motivated, and proficient with computers. Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Technology with specialization in Machine Learning & AI.

EXPERIENCE

LAUNCHPAD, AI

Principal Data Scientist

Jun. 2022 - Present

- Worked as an External Data Scientist for Levi Strauss & Co mentoring 25+ employees globally from multiple business verticals.
- Mentored a team to build a customer segmentation pipeline for deployment in the APAC region to optimize marketing efforts.
- Mentored another team to build a social listening and sentiment analysis pipeline to improve the LS&Co loyalty program
- Managed Launchpad.ai's Fellowship Program converting 60+ ML practitioners into full-fledged Data Scientists globally

Associate Data Scientist

Jan. 2022 - May 2022

- Developed a property listing image processing pipeline as a proposal for RE/MAX LLC that involves floor type classification, solar panel detection, HVAC vents detection, damage detection on the rooftop, etc.
- Created interactive notebooks contributing toward a full-fledged ML Bootcamp and upskilling Course for employees at LS&Co.
- Co-mentored a team of 10 fellows for Fellowship.ai, working on further enhancing the Product Designing Tool.

Machine Learning Fellow

Sep. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Developed a Stylegan-based Product Designing Tool for fluid and endless design generation for Handbags, apparel, cars, etc.
- Created the User Interface in plain Javascript and hosted it using Nginx and Gunicorn.

BANK OF AMERICA CONTINUUM INDIA

Software Developer I

Jul. 2019 - Jan. 2022

- Created a Breaks Management System for Derivatives and Future Options and Equities Transactions
- Scored 1st and 3rd Place for Service Ticket Matcher and Calls Transcript Generator respectively in an Internal AI Hackathon 2019 across 2k employees
- Scored 2nd Place for Code Completion API in Internal AI Hackathon 2020 held across 10k employees
- Mentored and Audited a Team through Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) under The Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act (CARES)
- · Have been awarded 5 times internally throughout my tenure in Bank of America

SYMPHONY AI

Summer Intern Apr. 2018 - Jun. 2018

Worked on Legal Document Information Extraction Pipeline for Krystal AI (a project based on Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing and Computer Vision)

ACHIEVEMENTS

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SMART SYSTEMS (ICSS - ADYPU)

Research Paper on "Semantic String Matching on Quora Question Pairs"

VIT SCSE IOT EXPO 2018 - WINNER

Developed a medicine dispensary system that would help elder or bed ridden patients

IIT NPTEL ONLINE CERTIFICATE (GOLD + ELITE)

NPTEL Online Course on Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms with consolidated score of 90%

PROJECTS

DENIAL OF DDOS

Generated a SNMP Parameters dataset based on simulated DDOS attack. This was used to detect and prevent the possibility of a DDOS attack by using various machine learning technique with an accuracy of 81%.

QUORA QUESTION PAIRING

Classification of 13 Million question pairs as similar or not with an accuracy of 82% by using fundamentals of Natural Language Processing and ML.

ANALYSIS OF IMAGE SEGMENTATION METHODS

Analysis on how different segmentation techniques can be applied for the detection of nuclie in cytological images. Used segmentation method to achieve an improved precision by 11%.